Finding Aid for the Medical Artifacts Collection
Eskind Biomedical Library Manuscripts Collection
- Box 46-A 445 Gynecologic instruments (uterine packing forceps), ca. 1900-1930. Donated by Martin A. Meacham, M.D., Class of 1907.
- Box 46-B 446 Box containing: one ether mask, one head mirror, two vaginal speculums, and one sphygmomanometer (incomplete), ca. 1900-1930. Donated by Martin A. Meacham, M.D., Class of 1907.
- Box 46-C 447 Box containing: fifteen syringes, ca. 1900-1930. Donated by Martin A. Meacham, M.D., Class of 1907.
- Box 47-A 448 Patent medicine. Box containing 27 patent medicines/drugs, ca. 1900-1930. Donated by Martin A. Meacham, M.D., Class of 1907.
- Box 47-B 449 Box containing 22 miscellaneous instruments, ca. 1900-1930. Donated by Martin A. Meacham, M.D., Class of 1907.
- Box 48 450 Box containing: enamel instrument box, miscellaneous enamel bowls, Dr. Meacham's leather driving gloves, a powder blower, an ear and ulcer syringe, and three phosphor-soda glasses, ca. 1900-1930. Donated by Martin A. Meacham, M.D., Class of 1907.
- Box 32 451 Nashville, University of and Tennessee, University of. Matriculation and General Ticket, Session of 1910-11 University of Nashville and University of Tennessee. Encased between two pieces of glass. Donated by Dean John Chapman, October, 1989.
- Box 32 452 Sanford, John H. Medical school grades of John H. Sanford, July 10, 1911. Encased between two pieces of glass. Donated by Dean Chapman, October, 1989.
- Box 32 453 Vanderbilt University School of Medicine. Alpha Omega Alpha. Alpha Omega Alpha charter for Vanderbilt University, March, 1923. Encased between two pieces of glass. Donated by Dean John Chapman, October, 1989.
- Box 66 456 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 121/4," Labeled: "Godfrey's S C." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 66 (currently in 311-B) 457 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 121/4," Labeled: "Ex. Limon." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 67 (currently in 311-B) 458 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 9.5," Labeled: "Pot. Sulph. P." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 67 459 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 83/4," Labeled: "Compressed Medicinal Lozen: Charcoal, Ten Grains,” John Wyeth & Brot., Incorporated, Manufacturing Chemists, Philadelphia. Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 67 460 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 81/4," Labeled: "Fol Conii." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990
- Box 67 461 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 8," Labeled: "Epsom Salt,” Dale & Co., York, Pa. Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 67 462 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 83/4," Labeled: "WM. Smith & Co, Pharmacists," York, PA." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 68 463 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 81/4," Labeled: "AC. Hy'Chlor. Dil." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 68 464 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 81/4," Labeled: "Lin. Saponis." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 68 465 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 81/4," Labeled: "Sp. Aeth. Nitr." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 68 466 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 81/4," Labeled: "Syr. Ac. Hydroid." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 68 467 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 73/4," Labeled: "Sp. Anisi. Nitr." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 68 468 Apothecary bottle, hand blown, 71/4," Labeled: "Tr. Calumb." Donated by Mrs. Rudolph H. Kampmeier, July, 1990.
- Box 73B 469A Buchanan, Margaret. Nurse's uniform, World War II, worn by (retired) 1st Lieutenant Margaret Buchanan. Worn at the end of the war, it contains a laurel wreath on the sleeve representing a unit commendation for meritorious service. There is also a leather purse and gloves which are part of the uniform. Donated by Margaret Buchanan, October, 1989.
- Room 311B 490 Wolfson, William. Pastel drawing by Susan Wilkes after the original by William Wolfson, 1994-1977. D rawing is of a doctor trying to free a naked woman from the clutches of a skeletal representation of Death. Inscribed "Drawn from an etching for Joe Akroyd in appreciation of many pleasant hours." Donated by John Simpson, M.D., 1991.
- Box 52 492 Doctor's bag. brown leather, ca 1900, which belonged to Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi. 14" x 7" x 8." Fair condition, leather has dry-rotted somewhat.). See also Obj 571-583 Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips.
- Box 19 495 Ampoule of standard ascorbic acid, distributed by the League of Nations, ca 1920. Donated by Lucille Adamson, Ph.D., in 1991
- Box 19 497 Rib Spreader used in T. B. work. Donated by Dr. Robert McCracken, September, 1992.
- Box 90 493 Survival Ration Crackers, contained in two large 5.5 pound cans. Ca. 1961-62, manufactured by the National Biscuit Company and Schulzean Burch Co. Description prepared by John Browe contained in box. Donated by John Browe, January, 1992.
- Vanderbilt Files 512 Vanderbilt University Dental Department. Class Composite of the graduating class of the Vanderbilt Dental Department, 1892-3. Mated with cardboard backing, and two photographic copies made form the original) Note: This composite is located in the Vanderbilt Files oversize Box 1 located in Historical Collections Room 311-A.
- Box 29 513 Flour bag, "National Emblem Self-Rising Enriched Flour" manufactured by Werthan for the F. G. Ellison Milling Co., of Cheddar, South Carolina. Donated by Dr. George V. Mann, 1992.
- Box 24 514 World War II Nazi medical officer's field kit. The four leather kits were manufactured in Germany between 1925 and 1939. One is inscribed with the name Michael Huber. The contents in the kit range form good to poor condition. Donated by Dr. Henry Carney, December, 1992.
- Box 19 515 Bransford Lewis Ureter Cystoscope. Some parts are missing, in very poor condition. Donated by Mrs. Virginia Sumpter, November, 1992.
- Box 19 516 Pair of wooden exercise weights ca. 1890. Donated by Mrs. Virginia Sumpter, November, 1992.
- Box 19 517 Stethoscope, ca. 1920. Donated by Mrs. Virginia Sumpter, November, 1992.
- Box 19 518 Head mirror, ca. 1920. Donated by Mrs. Virginia Sumpter, November, 1992.
- Box 19 519 Nine miscellaneous obstetrical instruments. Donated by Mrs. Virginia Sumpter, November, 1992.
- Box 24 520 Hamilton watch designed especially for the use of doctors, ca 1930s. Runs but not consistently. Donated by Dr. Henry M. Carney, January 14, 1993.
- Box 16 524 Japanese pharmaceutical scales in original wooden case. Ca. 1940. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 5, 1993.
- Box 16 525 Japanese pharmaceutical scales in original wooden case. Ca. 1940. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 526 Japanese glass thermometer in wooden case. Ca. 1940. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 527 Japanese pathology slide kit in wooden box. Three steel tools are inscribed with " H. Yanaguchi," Also there are four thick glass slides. Ca. 1940. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 528 Japanese blood transfusion kit in wooden box covered in black paper with silver symbols on top Printed with Japanese writing and "SMCO." Ca. 1940. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 529 Japanese pharmacy kit in brown leather case. contains a first aid kit and five phials of medicine. Ca. 1940. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 530 Vanderbilt University School of Medicine. Bronze medallion in black case. Inscribed: "Vanderbilt School of Medicine, A Century of Service, 1875" Known as the Centennial Medal. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 531 Vanderbilt University School of Medicine. Bronze medallion in white box. Inscribed: "Vanderbilt School of Medicine, A Century of Service, 1875" Known as the Centennial Medal. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 16 532 Scott, H. William (Society) Bronze medallion from the H. William Scott, Jr. Society. Contained in white box. Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 533 McSwain, Horace Barton. Photograph, framed, of Barton McSwain in Navy uniform, ca. 1945 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 534 McSwain, John Horace. Photograph, framed, of John Horace McSwain, ca. 1945 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 535 Daniel, Rollin. Photograph, framed, of Rollin Daniel, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 536 Haggard, W. D. Photograph, framed and signed of W. D. Haggard, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 537 Heuer, George. Photograph, black framed and signed of George Heuer, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 538 Heuer, George. Photograph, white framed and signed of George Heuer, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 539 Whipple, Allen O. Photograph, framed and signed of Allen O. Whipple, ca. 1935 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 540 Bigger, J. A. Photograph, framed and signed of J. A. Bigger, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 541 Lehman, Edwin. Photograph, framed and signed of Edwin Lehman, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 542 Orr, Thomas G. Photograph, framed and signed of Thomas G. Orr, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 543 Foot, N. Chandler. Photograph, framed and of N. Chandler Foot, ca. 1945 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 544 Johnson, George S. Photograph, framed and signed of George S. Johnson, ca. 1945 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 545 Blalock, Alfred. Photograph, framed and signed of Alfred Blalock, ca. 1935 (glass broken). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 546 Goodpasture, Ernest W. Photograph, framed and signed of Ernest Goodpasture, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 547 Brooks, Barney. Photograph, framed and signed of Barney Brooks, ca. 1935 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 548 Lawson, Robert "Jim." Photograph, framed and signed of Dr. Robert "Jim" Lawson, ca. 1940 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 549 Vanderbilt University School of Medicine Department of Surgery. Photograph, framed group photo of the Department of Surgery, ca. 1945 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 550 Vanderbilt University School of Medicine. Class of 1927. Photograph, framed group photo of "Freshman Quinqs, Saturday May 14, 1977,” (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 13 551 McSwain, Horace Barton. Photographs, three framed unidentified photos. One is of an individual and two are group photos. Possibly from the University of Virginia, and (or) New York Hospital, ca. 1935. (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Shelf 12 552 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the American Surgical Society awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. in 1962 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Shelf 12 553 McSwain, Horace Barton. Citation, framed, from Vanderbilt for distinguished service awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on September 1, 1970. (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 554 McSwain, Horace Barton. License, framed, from the State Board of Medical Examiners of Tennessee issued to Barton McSwain, M.D. on September 6, 1930. (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 555 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from Vanderbilt University Hospital awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on August 1, 1931 in recognition of service as intern in the Surgical Service (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 556 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the University of Virginia Hospital awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on January 4, 1934, in recognition of service as intern, assistant resident, and resident on surgery (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 557 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the American College of Surgeons awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on October 25, 1937 in recognition of being accepted as a fellow (paint chipping on gold frame). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 558 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the American Board of Surgery awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on November 15, 1939 in recognition of passing the qualifying examination (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 559 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the Southeastern Surgical Congress awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on February 4, 1940 in recognition of being admitted as a fellow (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 560 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the Society of Sigma Xi awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on May 6, 1948 on occasion of his election to membership. (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 561 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the Southern Surgical Association awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. in December 1949 in recognition of being elected a fellow (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 562 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the American Cancer Society awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on August 31, 1962 for merit (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 563 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, Distinguished Service Award from the Tennessee Division of the American Cancer Society awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on September 25, 1962 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 564 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from Alpha Omega Alpha awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. in 1963 in recognition of being elected a member (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 565 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from Vanderbilt Alumni Association awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. in recognition of his Service as President of Vanderbilt Medical Alumni Association, 1967-68 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 566 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from Vanderbilt Medical Alumni Association awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on May 14, 1977 in recognition of 50 years membership (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 567 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, leather-framed, from Vanderbilt University awarded to Barton McSwain, M.D. on May 23, 1980 in recognition of 50 years of service to medicine. (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 568 Vanderbilt University Alumni Association. Plate, solid sterling silver inlaid with 24 kt gold. Official Vanderbilt University plate issued by the Alumni Association. Limited edition from Franklin Mint, Numbered 154. Contained in white case (excellent condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 14 569 McSwain, Horace Barton. Certificate, framed, from the Society for Surgery of the Alimentary Tract certifying that Barton McSwain, M.D. is a founding member, dated 1962. (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Anne McSwain Colson, March 9, 1993.
- Box 44 570 Microscope, Italian, compound monocular with three lens adjustments (10.5x, 52x, and 100x). Black, circular stage, horseshoe base, mirror, and silver colored fine and coarse adjustment knobs. Contained in wooden case, and manufactured by Officine Galileo, serial number 70247. Donated by Henry M. Carney, M.D. March 15, 1993.
- Box 28 571 Medicine case, brown leather, ca. 1890. Contains 3 trays of various labeled medicine bottles and a compartment containing empty capsules (Good condition except for medicine). Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 572 Case, brown leather ca. 1900, containing 11 phials of medicine. Gold lettering of the name Dr. J. M. Phillips on the front flap (in poor condition). Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 573 Case, black leather ca. 1910 containing 10 phials of medicine. Inside flap which snaps is imprinted in gold lettering with: The Abbot Alkaloidal Co. Chicago, Ill." (fair condition) Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 574 Dr. Roger Tycos Sphygmomanometer," manufactured by Taylor Instrument Co. Rochester, NY. Sold by the A. S. Aloe Co., St. Louis, Mo., Ca. 1910. In Black leather covered box with snapping flap. (in good condition except for rubber bulb and tubing) Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 575 Stethoscope. ca. 1910, in brown canvass bag. Manufactured by "Douglas." Tubing is missing. Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 576 Case, black leather tri-fold, containing various medical instruments including: four scalpels, three clamps, and a pair of tweezers. (Instruments are rusty and the leather is in poor condition.) Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 577 Obstetrical suture, ca. 1910, manufactured by W. D. Young & Co., Boston. Two phials are in original labeled boxes. Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 578 Ethyl chloride local anaesthesia tube. Patented in 1902 and manufactured by the Gerbauer Chemical Company, Cleveland, Ohio. In original green box, and contains instructions (in excellent condition). Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 579 Otoscope in black leather pouch, patented July 22, 1913. Manufactured by Weder Mfg., Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Four attachments (good condition). Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 580 Miscellaneous medical instruments, ca. 1910, including: a clamp, tweezers, scissors, and a tooth puller. Stored in a manilla envelope (instruments are rusty). Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 581 Glass thermometer ca. 1910, in an aluminum twist fashion carrying tube with a chain at end. Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 582 Glass beaker ca. 1900, with a graduated scale etched on the side, 6" x 1." Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Box 28 583 Hypodermic needles and syringes, ca. 1900. Various assortment contained in three aluminum cases, four boxes, and one leather case. Stored in a plastic bag (all are in fair condition). Donated by the family of Dr. J. M. Phillips of Crenshaw, Mississippi.
- Room 311-A 584 Brooks, Barney. Brass desk weight made by Dr. Barney Brooks, and used by Dr. Henry Carney for 55 years. Donated by Dr. Henry M. Carney, March 29, 1993.
- Box 88 585 Sebrell, William H. Plaque, red and black in the shape of a shield with two brass plates on back inscribed: "To W. H. Sebrell, Jr.. Jan 22, 1965 Tokyo Society of Medical Sciences and Faculty of Medicine University of Tokyo" (Good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 586 Sebrell, William H. Plaque, wood and brass presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., by the Food and Nutrition Council of Greater New York, Inc. on May 8, 1968 in recognition of distinguished service (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 587 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed, presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., on September 9, 1946, verifying appointment to the regular corps of the Public Health Service (good condition) Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 588 Sebrell, William H. License, framed, from the Board of Medical Examiners of Maryland certifying that William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., is qualified to practice medicine. Dated October, 8, 1950 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 589 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed, honorary degree of Doctor of Science presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., from Alfred University on June 5, 1955 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 590 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed, from Phi Beta Kappa certifying that William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., was made a member on June 11, 1955. (good condition) Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 591 Sebrell, William H. License, framed, from the University of the State of New York Education Department certifying that William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D. is qualified to practice medicine. Dated August 31, 1955 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 592 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed Conrad A. Elvehjem Award presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., in 1968 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 593 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed, from the American Institute of Nutrition presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., on April 18, 1968 in recognition of a distinguished career (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 594 Sebrell, William H. Plaque, resolution hand-lettered and laminated on a wooden board, presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., by the Research Corporation on October 25, 1968 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 595 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed, University of Virginia Sesquicentennial Award presented to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., in 1969 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 596 Sebrell, William H. Certificate, framed, from the Society of the South Pole certifying that William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D., set foot on the geographic South Pole. Dated January 26, 1970 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 597 Sebrell, William H. Plaque, wooden, from the American Family Physicians' Editorial Advisory Board awarded to to William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D. in appreciation of long service, undated (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 598 Sebrell, William H. Photograph, black and white, framed, of William H. Sebrell, Jr., M.D. in a military uniform shaking the hand of an unidentified person, ca. 1946 (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 599 Sebrell, William H. Photograph, color, framed, of six men who were directors of the National Institutes of Health. Description of photo is on back (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.
- Box 88 600 Sebrell, William H. Diploma, from the University of Virginia awarding the degree of Doctor of Medicine to William H. Sebrell, Jr. on June 16, 1925. Rolled and contained in a mailing tube (good condition). Donated by Mrs. Helena Sebrell, April 2, 1993.